recording in progress.
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen, and
welcome to the January 26th meeting of
Cheyenne's governing body. Madame Clerk,
will you call the role?
>> Mr. White,
>> present.
>> Mr. Wolf,
>> here.
>> Dr. Aldrich,
>> present.
>> Mayor Collins
>> here.
>> Dr. Emmens
>> Mr. Esabel
>> here.
>> Mr. Lebornne
>> Mr. Moody
>> here.
>> Dr. Renie
>> present.
>> Mr. Crave
>> All members are present. We do have a
quorum.
>> Would you please join me in the pledge
of allegiance?
Ladies and gentlemen, we have uh one
little item that's not on our agenda,
and that is that uh Dr. Rainey was the
president of our city council for the
last year. Uh I think for a
record-breaking 10th time. Um so I'm not
sure where he's going to find room in
his house to put a tenth plaque, but
we're not going to not give him one. uh
and thank him for his service as the
president of our city council. So, if
you join me in congratulating him,
please. [applause]
>> Next item, please.
>> Number four, consent agenda. All agenda
items listed with the designation of CA
are considered to be routine items by
the governing body and will be enacted
by one motion. There will be no separate
discussion on these items unless a
member of the governing body so requests
and support by two other members is
received. Any item removed from the
consent agenda will be considered in its
normal sequence on the agenda.
>> All right. Are there any items a member
of the governing body would like to
remove? Yes, Dr. Aldridge.
>> Number 11, please.
>> That is a reappropriation of our budget.
>> Concur.
Number 11 is removed. Anybody else?
Hearing none, I would entertain a
motion.
>> So move.
>> Second.
>> Moved by Dr. Aldridge, seconded by Mr.
White. All those in favor of the consent
agenda with number 11 removed, please
signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> I. Those opposed. The consent agenda is
approved again with number 11 being
removed, it'll be considered in its
normal place on the uh agenda.
>> Number six, ordinance third reading
creating chapter 1.28. 28 administrative
inspection warrants, establishing
authority for their issuance and
amending the municipal code of the city
of Cheyenne, Wyoming to authorize
certain city officials as specified to
apply for administrative inspection
warrants.
>> Two things. One is that uh I see a lot
of new faces here. Again, thank you.
It's exciting to have people come and
participate in our process. Um, if you
want to come speak to us, all we ask is
that you come up to either one of the
two microphones, push the button till
the green light comes on, and then
identify yourself by giving us your
name, and then we have three minutes to
uh take your testimony, please. Uh, I
would share with you though that at the
last meeting of our public services
committee, the recommendation is to
postpone this item for two weeks. We
heard from you guys at the last meeting
um that we probably need to take a
little time and uh and look at this
ordinance. And so that is a
recommendation from a public services
committee and what I expect will happen
tonight. Um I guess I would ask
maybe we would hold off on some of your
testimony if you'd like. Um but if this
does not get postponed, everybody here
that wants to speak will be able to
speak. Um and so at this time we'll open
it up to the public and see if anybody
wants to speak on administrative
warrants.
Go ahead, sir.
>> Oh, one more thing if I could. You guys,
it it's really hard for people online to
hear and people back in this part of the
audience. If you don't pull that
microphone right up to about two inches
from your mouth and talk into it, if you
turn around and look at the crowd, we
can't hear you. So, if you do that just
for us, we'd really appreciate that.
Thank you.
>> Sir, Mr. Mayor, members of the council,
thank you for the opportunity to speak.
My name is Gary Pew. I'm a resident of
Cheyenne. I live in Ward One.
I'm here today to oppose Chapter 1.28
administrative warrants because
administrative warrants raise serious
constitutional concerns and directly
affect the residents of our city. This
issue is not abstract and it's not
partisan. It goes to the heart of the
Fourth Amendment in the relationship
between local communities and government
authority. The Fourth Amendment
guarantees that people are secure in
their homes and that the government may
not search or seize without a warrant
issued by an independent impartial judge
based on probable cause. That safeguard
exists for one reason to ensure that no
government agency can act as judge and
enforcer at the same time.
Administrative warrants violate that
principle. Unlike judicial warrants,
administrative warrants are issued
internally by government agencies.
Remember, a municipal judge is appointed
by the mayor and the council.
Administrative warrants are not reviewed
or approved by an independent judge.
When an agency authorizes its
enforcement actions, the constitutional
check designed to protect the public is
removed. That is exactly the kind of
unchecked authority the Fourth Amendment
is written to prevent. The Supreme Court
has consistently held that home deserves
the highest level of constitutional
protection. Entering a private residence
without consent generally requires a
judicial warrant. Administrative
warrants simply do not meet that
standard. They bypass judicial oversight
and weaken the constitutional barrier
that protects residents from
unreasonable searches and seizures. This
matter is a local is at a local level
because constitutional violations do not
occur in theory. They occur on our
streets and in our doorsteps. Entering a
private residence without consent
generally requires a judicial warrant.
Admin administrative warrants simply do
not meet that standard.
[clears throat] When residents fear that
the government agents enter their home
without an independent judge's approval,
trust erodess. People become less
willing to cooperate with law
enforcement, report crimes, or engage
with local institutions. That loss of
trust harms public safety for everyone.
Some argue that administrative warrants
are necessary for efficiency, but
efficiency has never been a
constitutional justification. The
Constitution was intentionally designed
to slow the government down when
fundamental rights are at stake.
Convenience cannot override due process.
This is a slippery precedent. If
agencies are permitted to bypass
independent judicial warrants in one
area of enforcement, that authority can
expand. Rights that depend on a person
targeted are not rights at all. The
Fourth Amendment either protects
everyone in this city or it protects no
one. City councils are responsible to
uphold constitutional values and protect
their communities. Speaking out against
the use of administrative warrants is
not obstructing the law. It is about
insisting that the law be enforced
within constitutional limits. I urge
this council to affirm its commitment to
the Fourth Amendment, to judicial
oversight, and to the principle that no
government agency should have the power
to police itself at the expense of our
residents rights. Thank you for your
time.
>> You did almost exactly three minutes.
Thank you, Mr. Pew.
Representative, welcome to our meeting.
>> Thank you, Mr. Mayor.
My name is Anne Lucas and I do not live
in the city of Cheyenne. I live in the
county, but I am the house district rep.
I am the house rep for district 43,
which encompasses a fair little bit of
the city of Cheyenne and I have heard
from many constituents and some of whom
are here this evening and it's great to
see you folks here. Um, so I just have a
few comments. Mr. Mayor and council
members, I want to be really clear on
this. I fully support the city's ability
to act immediately when there is a real
emergency. Fires, gas leaks, structural
collapse, or other situations that can
put lives at risk. I also believe that
laws should be enacted when they must be
enacted and not because we can enact
them. And I don't think that this
ordinance is limited to emergent
situations.
I looked at the title 15 and um there
are three chapters that don't apply in
this ordinance and they happen to be the
historic design guideline,
solar access permit system and house
numbers
and every other bit of the building code
applies in this ordinance including um
energy conf conservation code. This is a
a bill about code code code enforcement.
Um,
none of these really are emergencies or
are so seldom emergencies. I if if it
was, you could still do it because it
would be an emergency.
A missing permit, a failed inspection
signoff, an unapproved alteration, or a
long-standing maintenance issue doesn't
suddenly become a life-threatening
situation because simply because an
inspector can't gain access.
Yet, this ordinance allows inter
administrative inspection warrants to be
used for all of title 15 with the
exception of those three chapters that I
me mentioned. This is the problem. If
the issue is truly ex exigent, a fire
hazard, a gas leak, a building is going
to fall down and kill somebody, we
already have the ex the required
authority to deal with those
emergencies. You don't have to go and
get a warrant to put out a fire or keep
people from getting killed. So, this is
an exigent. The city should always be
able to require a judicial warrant
reviewed by a judge with probable cause
and the scope clearly defined. Th that
is not an unreasonable burden. It is a
constitutional baseline. This ordinance
blurs the line between emergency
response and ordinary enforcement. It
treats routine compliance matters as if
they justify the same intrusion as a
life safety emergency.
And they don't.
Private property rights are not an
inconvenience to be worked around.
They're a boundary that requires care,
restraint, and judicial oversight. I
urge you to amend this ordinance so that
immediate access to private property is
limited strictly to genuine safety
emergencies.
All
>> you understand your time is up.
>> Oh, I'm not used to that.
>> Yeah, you guys do it to me all the time
when I come to They do it all the time
to me at the legislature to say you're
up and sit down, Mr. Mayor. So,
>> well, somebody would say point of order,
but I understand and I appreciate your
time, folks. Thank you very much.
>> Made your point. I really appreciate you
being here this evening. Thank you.
[snorts]
>> Good evening.
>> Good evening, mayor and member members
of the council. My name is Kathy
Sigliano and I am a resident here in
Laramie County. I'd like to speak in
opposition to the proposed ordinance.
Last week, three of you from a committee
of four agreed to postpone and I have
received emails from Councilman Moody,
Esabel White, as well as Councilwoman
Emmens and Aldridge saying that they
would support support a postponement.
When I asked in an email back if
amendments and revisions would be
submitted to you all by today's meeting
if you would still vote to postpone, I
only received a response of yes from
Michelle Aldridge. The postponement was
not conditional. I am asking that if a
revision is given, you still postpone to
allow public comment to give feedback
and address any concerns they may have.
I I ask you give at least more than a
few hours. Two weeks would be nice. But
in event you still move to vote tonight,
I will say this. History has a funny way
of repeating itself, especially when
people convenient convince themselves
that the time right now is okay for the
government to be used in a gently,
responsible, or only on the right people
time of matter. The British crown
thought the same thing in the 18th
century when it issued general warrants,
vague permissions that allowed officials
to search homes, businesses, and
property without sus specific suspicion.
No names, no clear limits, no real
accountability, just trust. Those
warrants were widely unpopular,
routinely abused, and became one of the
very reasons we have the Fourth
Amendment. Our founders didn't add
protections against unreasonable
searches because they were paranoid or
dramatic. They did it because they had
lived under a system where government
agents could enter property first,
justify it later. This ordinance walks
dangerously close to that same line.
Calling these warrants noncriminal
doesn't make them harmless. A forced
entry onto private property is still a
search. Allowing unelected officials to
obtain warrants based on broad standards
like inspection or safety concerns
without owner consent or clear probable
cause is exactly the kind of authority
that the fourth amendment was designed
to restrain.
And what we are seeing here is a blatant
disregard to this community by refusing
to take into consideration any
amendments or suggestions from the
community.
We are being asked once again to trust
the government. We always use this power
wisely. History both British and
American suggest otherwise. Private
property rights are not an inconvenience
to be managed. They are a constitutional
boundary. When government starts
treating that boundary as optional, it
doesn't stop with vacant buildings or
unpop unpopular owners. It expands.
Wyoming has never been a place that
governs by trust. We govern by limits,
transparency, and respect for indiv
individual rights. I urge the council to
remember the oath you took and reject
this ordinance. Thank you.
>> Welcome back.
Good evening, mayor and council members.
My name is Patricia McCoy and I have
been a resident of Cheyenne for 18
years. I am here today to formally
recommend and support this body in
postponing the vote for this ordinance
for two weeks as recommended by the
committee. This time is necessary for
the council to review a corrected
version of the draft provided by an
attorney and fellow citizen who is
willing to help this body pass an
ordinance that actually aligns with the
Wyoming constitution and Wyoming Supreme
Court presidents and allows the public
time to review the amended draft prior
to it being voted to pass. Before I
address this ordinance, I must address
the culture of this chamber. Rule four
on the general meeting information
plaque outside this very room states
proper decorum must be observed and
courtesy given to members of the
governing body you city staff and
members of the public. While I apologize
for whispering or speaking too loudly at
the last meeting unaware that that small
sign was out there. My apologies for
that. I noticed a glaring double
standard. Certain members of this
governing body were allowed to rudely
interrupt, cut off, and talk down to the
public throughout the meeting without a
single reprimand from the chair until
the attack became personal against one
individual. Yet, you were quick to rec
reprimand those of us in the back. To
enforce rules strictly against the
public while allowing council members to
ignore the courtesy clause of rule 4 is
the definition of hypocrisy. These
behaviors are arbitrary and capriccious.
We are not uneducated
or misinformed as some have suggested.
We agree with you. The abandoned
buildings are an issue and they need
attention. However, we refuse to accept
that the city convenience should come at
the expense of our rights. Our concerns
are rooted in the strong privacy
protections of article 1, section 4. The
amended version provided by this
attorney offers the constitutional guard
rails this ordinance is currently
missing. It provides authority to the
circuit court ensuring a state level
judge reviews these warrants rather than
a cityapp appointed official. It defines
abandonment with clear measurable
standards 180 days and utility
disconnection preventing the city from
using blight as a pretext to enter
homes. and it explicitly bans warrants
for simple nuisance or zoning violations
that are observable from the street. I
urge you to read this corrected version.
We are educated enough to know that when
any government official says blindly
trust us, it is a time and cause for
concern. Let's take two weeks to choose
an ordinance that solves problems
through the law rather than through the
sacrifice of our privacy. Thank you.
Folks, I'll remind you it is the
intention of this governing body, I
believe, to postpone this ordinance. So,
>> go ahead, sir.
Push the button.
>> Push the button.
[clears throat]
>> There we go.
>> There you go.
>> Hi, this is Peter Seel. I live here in
uh precinct 2-1. I'm a precinct
committeeman for the GOP. And very
simply, uh, if we already have
ordinances to take care of
any questions of safety,
um, fire hazard or a building falling
over or being abandoned, these things
are already on the books. And it's just
common sense for anybody who knows these
two things are on the books to take care
of any problems that are existing.
Why have another one? It just makes
everybody very suspicious. And if you
could have simply a comparison of the
two and why you need this to clarify any
sus or to clarify the points of need
and to uh just kind of dissu the
doubt and suspicion.
It's it's a suspicious thing to have two
sets of rules that do the same thing.
Would this be causing a um
kind of a secret or unspoken need to go
inspect somebody's home is there
suspicious people in this whole the
whole city and it'll be the county
eventually. So I think if you clarify
why clearly we've already got the rules
now we need more for what?
So I don't want this to occur and if it
can become up clear and needful
people would not be so suspicious. A lot
everybody I talk to at coffees in the
morning and uh anywhere I go and I talk
about you know you read it and it's
dupistic.
So thank you very much.
>> Appreciate you being here.
>> Sure.
>> Anyone else want to speak to us?
Good evening, sir.
>> Good evening. I'm uh Abe Mendes, a
resident of Cheyenne or whatnot. Um I
just want to speak against this. It
seems very uh I came hopefully I'm
prepared people have speeches and stuff.
Um, I just found out about, not found
out about, that's what I've been seeing
it. And part of what I like about
Wyoming, small government, everybody
kind of leaves, you know, I guess just
the spirit of small government, people
get left alone. The way I understood
this in my in my brain is, you know, you
guys want to use it or not necessarily
you guys, but government wants to use it
to get rid of the buildings. Correct.
That that are problems. Yes, no one is
denying that. But what happens in my
mind, we'll get the buildings taken care
of and all that. Well, I've never
necessarily seen a law get retracted or
a government gets smaller on its own
accord. So, we'll get rid of the
buildings that are problems. Then what
happens next? Is it like, oh, hey, we,
you know, we got to do something with
this. Let's start going into I don't
know. I'm sorry. I'm kind of nervous
here. let's start going into people's
homes for this is an extreme of course
but there's not to say that government
doesn't go to extremes let's start
issuing warrants and this or that maybe
hey that guy's car hasn't moved in 3
weeks or whatever is this house
abandoned is it not let's issue a
warrant for him see what happens right
and ult this might be me being paranoid
ultimately I could see it being you know
just a step
just that much into where he we have a
bigger government and maybe it could
just I could see it being used in a
world where it's just to and I hope I'm
wrong. I really want to be wrong, but
it's used as a way to drum up more
business or whatever for our government
getting, you know, say iron inspection
doesn't pass. So now I have to bring my
electricity up to code or something.
Well, I need my permits. I need this and
that and the other. Correct. Right. You
can't just build willy-nilly as far as I
know in Cheyenne. Everything has to be
up to code and we need a building
permit. Unless I'm incorrect. Right.
You're correct.
>> Right. So, that's my big thing. I just I
don't like it because it seems to me to
be a step towards bigger government,
however big or small it is, but I'd like
to keep our government small. And I
understand you guys have to get stuff
done, too, of course. But, um, I believe
everybody else before me just said it
already better. There's already
ordinances and things that are in place
that can help handle the blight and
decayed buildings that need to get
handled. That's all I had to say about
that. Thank you guys for uh listening to
me. Appreciate it.
>> Come back again. You did well. Thank
you.
>> Representative, welcome.
>> Hey, thanks mayor and members of
council. Lee Fer Ward one.
You know what? You know, you mentioned
that you know this this body seems like
it's going to postpone this for two
weeks. With a few of you that I have
talked to, I want to say thanks because
it seemed like this came came about
pretty fast. There's a lot of knee-jerk
reactions. What do we, you know, is the
city going to come into our houses and,
you know, un unwarrantless and violate
our Fourth Amendment rights and all
these different things. But for you guys
to actually take the time, take the two
weeks, maybe put the sideboards on it
that it needs in order to address the
concerns of everybody that's shown up in
the last couple meetings, I just want to
thank you.
>> Appreciate you being here. I know you're
going to be busy, a lot of you guys here
in the next few weeks. Um, so it's nice
you're here tonight, sir.
Colin Crossman, Ward One. And uh
>> Sorry, sorry, I didn't catch your name.
>> Colin Crossman, Ward One, and I'm here
in my personal capacity and not with
that of my employer. Um, since you are
going to to uh potentially
postpone this, I just wanted to put
something for in your heads to think
about while you're thinking about it
over the next two weeks. One of the big
problems I see with this ordinance is
that it is being pitched to the to the
people of Cheyenne as we have these
abandoned properties and we have uh
situations where a house is or a
property is burned and the uh the fire
department might not be able to get back
in. However, there's this one line in
here. Cause shall be deemed to exist if
reasonable legislative administrative
standards for conducting a routine
periodic and area inspection are
satisfied with respect to the particular
premises. That has nothing to do with
abandoned properties. That has nothing
to do with burned properties. That is a
systematic
routine inspection ordinance that can
cover every property in that district.
That is not how this is being sold. That
is in this ordinance right now. And if
that remains there, I think that's part
of the problem here because that is the
very definition of a general warrant.
And my fellow member of the bar uh in
the council might say, but camera versus
uh San Francisco. Sure, the Supreme
Court has authorized these things. the
Supreme Court of the United States. As
we have uh as we discussed last time,
the Wyoming Constitution's Fourth
Amendment protection is slightly
different and hence this has not been uh
to my own knowledge tested under the
Wyoming Constitution. But just because
the Supreme Court has issued a ruling in
camera doesn't mean it's a good ruling.
Dread Scott Piv Fergensson
Cororamatsu,
thank you very much.
Thanks for being here again this evening
and thanks for the uh constitutional
lesson. I I read it and I missed one
word difference and you're right. Thank
you.
>> Anyone else
online? Who do you have
>> Miss Trujillo? You can go ahead and
unmute yourself.
>> Mr. Heo, welcome.
>> Hello. Can you hear me? We can Tamara.
Thank you.
>> All right. Well, Tamara Trill, Ward One,
thank you, Mr. Mayor, Council, I'm not
going to repeat myself because of course
you've heard from us and everybody for
the past few weeks and you know,
starting with tonight's even testimony
with Mr. Gary Pew, you already know how
we feel and how we think. Um,
I just want to do a couple reminders
that, you know, you are voted in by the
people for the people, not for the
government.
Uh, so tonight, your vote to postpone
is
a nice courtesy, but I would really ask
for it to be tabled and just redone from
the beginning.
Um,
with that I just want to say and well I
want to bring attention and remind the
public out there is an article from
file May 20th 2021
and the title of that is high court and
this is Wyoming Wyoming high court finds
cop lied in hemp case and centers the
prosecutor. computer
proc uh let's see the Laram County
senior assistant district attorney
Singleton allowed the DCI special agent
Briggs to falsely testify.
Later they were asked to correct the
record for the court but instead they
bolstered the lie.
All this stemmed from a suggested phone
call from a firefighter
claiming that their hemp farm was a
marijuana farm.
I'm going to leave this
as proof as why I want this tabled and
redone from the beginning for its
intended purposes
of abandoned properties. Thank you for
your time.
Mr. Wassenberger, welcome.
>> Thanks for being here, Representative.
>> Absolutely. Thank you, Mayor. Uh, thank
you, city council, for having me
tonight. Jacob Wasabberger, Ward One. I
just would like to ask um I would just
like to say thank you for uh considering
doing a postpone on the scheduling of
this uh new ordinance that you brought
forth. Uh some of the things that I
think are a little concerning which I'm
kind of rehashing what a lot of people
have said is uh it it very much uh
closely gets into the uh concern with
our Fourth Amendment rights. Uh I
believe your guys's intention was for it
to be good. You know, we've got some
abandoned properties. We need a solution
to be able to um
resolve some of these issues. Uh, one of
the things that I would think about is,
uh, you know, when we're trying to
determine if a building is abandoned or
not, is there, you know, any other type
of, uh, checks and balances before just
seeing that a building is completely
empty? You know, I mean, uh, is there a
check with the board of utilities to see
if uh, uh, bills are still being paid?
Um, is there any checks with the county
assessor if property taxes are being
paid on it or things like that? Um, so
those are just some of the things that I
would like to have just put out there
and thought um when you're considering
maybe what would be considered an
abandoned property. But uh one of the
things that I think is real concerning
with this uh ordinance is um while it
the intention of it is to be good, it
there is that concern that over time you
get rid of the solution that you have.
Well, if we keep that ordinance in
check, you know, what's going to happen
to the homeowner that maybe has a home
built in 1995 and so they don't have a
building that's up to code and new
ordinance codes requires there to be ice
shelter dams on the roof. you know, is
that going to be, you know, maybe that's
not exactly what you guys are gonna, you
know, come and uh ask somebody or bug
somebody about, but you know, what
happens when we have a new city council
here and they see that that's not up to
code and if they want to require that
there needs to be ice shelter dams built
on that home. Well, with the cost of
living, I mean, it's gotten so high for
a lot of people. That's, you know,
trying to get $18,000 out of pocket to
uh do some of these new building codes
is not going to be a reality for people.
And something like that, I mean, that's
not something you can make a claim on
your insurance to have the building
codes uh recovered. Typically, that
happens when the building comes
completely down and you have to uh
replace the home and get it up to
building code. So, I appreciate that you
guys are taking that into consideration
to postpone this. Um, ultimately I think
there needs to be kind of like what the
previous speaker had said. Um, it may it
needs to either be completely redone or
we need to leave the warranting issuing
with the courts and not so much with our
city council. So, uh, thank you guys for
your time. Um, I know you guys have a
tough job and so I thank you for having
me here tonight.
>> Appreciate you being here.
Anyone else online?
>> Mr. Miller, you should be able to unmute
yourself.
>> Mr. Miller.
>> Uh, yes. Hi. Can you hear me?
>> We can, sir.
>> Okay. Just one moment here. Um, okay.
Here we go.
>> Introduce yourself first, please.
>> Well, this is Charles Miller. Um, I just
have a few things to say here.
Give me just one moment. I'm sorry.
I got a little bit of issues with my
device. Um, mayor, council, um, I am
submitting an amendment uh to section
1.28020.
The amendment fixes the three fatal
flaws in this ordinance. First, it
replaces the unconstitutional area
inspection standard with particularized
probable cause. You cannot search a home
just because the neighborhood is old.
You need a you need specific evidence of
a specific violation. Second, it moves
the authority to a circuit court judge.
The city cannot ask its own municipal
court for permission to search its own
citizens. That is a conflict of
interest. Uh we demand state level
oversight. Third, and most importantly,
it incorporates the protections of
Wyoming statutes 3571046.
There, this statute explicitly forbids
secret searches. It requires that an
officer present their credentials and
the warrant to the owner before
entering. My amendment forces this
ordinance to comply with state law. It
ensures that no warrant could be issued
for a surprise inspection when the owner
is not home. If you vote against this
amendment, you're voting for general
warrants based on geography, city
controlled judges rubber stamping city
requests, and secret searches that
violate state statute. Do not put the
city in that liability box. Adopt the
instrument.
>> That's all.
>> Thank you.
>> Who else you got, Jennifer?
>> Mr. Jacobson, you should be able to
unmute yourself.
Thank you.
>> Go ahead, Mr. Jacobson.
>> City Council, can you hear me?
>> We can. And identify yourself, please.
>> This Stephen G. Jacobson.
I think you should vote against this.
I sent to Dr. Emmens
after the last city council meeting. She
announced that she was going to be the
chairman of the public service committee
meeting. and I sent her an email
asking her specifically
to have the
uh
fire chief and the
city
ordinance
inspector provide over the last two
years specific examples
of situations where this ordinance would
be applicable.
and necessary.
And I went to that meeting, the public
service meeting.
None of those were addressed. Not a
single one.
I've heard a lot of hand ringing from
various people about how much this is
needed. But I've never heard one iota
statement as to why this really needs to
be needed, why this ordinance needs to
be put into place.
There's a lot of suggestions.
There's some innuendos,
but nothing specific.
So, if you want to sell this to the
public, I would strongly recommend you
put together a task force that talks
about why this is really needed.
And I also submit to you that what Mr.
Miller just said to you is critical
because
the ordinance is in violation of state
law which says specifically that it has
to be a district court not a city court.
So I urge you to table this to not
consider this further and start from
scratch. Thank you very much.
>> Jennifer, do you have more?
Mr. Bowling, you can go ahead and unmute
yourself.
>> Good evening, council. My name is Philip
Bowling. I'm in W two. I do have a 3
minute and 10 second speech, so I'm
going to get going because I know it's
right there. So, I have taken time to
think carefully about what to say and
about what words might make an actual
difference. I've heard repeatedly that
people are afraid and that we should
quote trust you quote because fear is
not your intent. But intent is something
that we is not something we guess at. It
is defined by what is written. And what
is written here does not resolve those
fears. Trust is a two-way street and
currently we are struggling with trust
in this moment.
Throughout the process, residents have
raised serious and thoughtful concerns.
The Fourth Amendment, Wyoming
Constitution, Supreme Court, Wyoming
Statutes, private private property
rights, and the loss of liberty. We've
also raised concerns about the lack of
clarity, undefined terms,
potential costs and fines, and the fact
that this authority uh would only be
used rarely. What I would have What I
have not heard is a clear limiting
principle, something that ensures this
authority will not be expanded beyond
its original intent or become normal
over time. These are not emotional
objections. They are legal,
constitutional and practical concerns.
People have also offered to help.
Attorneys have offered volunteer their
time to assist in rewriting this
ordinance and the city of the Cheyenne
board of realtors have offered to sit
down and discuss it. Yet, historically,
the city has often declined that outside
expertise. What is frustrating is that
the council's appears willing to listen
closely to their employees while being
far less receptive to members out
outside of the community, many of whom
are also trained professionals in law,
real estate, construction, and safety. I
also find it ironic that the council has
emphasized the need for other ordinances
because quote, "People want them quote."
Well, in this case, you are hearing
clearly and repeatedly why many people
do not want this one. [snorts] What I'm
hearing is a fear-based moral argument
for why this ordinance should pass while
the public's fear of government
overreach is being dismissed. If trust
were a trust alone were enough, we would
not need a constitution. I want to close
by re referencing the oath each of you
took to honestly and faithfully
discharge the duties of your office to
the best of your ability. I am a
realtor, but I'm here speaking on my
behalf of myself and I have a similar
duty to my clients. Acting the best of
my ability means bringing in independent
experts when decisions are complex and
consequential. I do not see this council
meaningfully engaging in experts who are
not employed by the city to evaluate
whether this ordinance is necessary,
properly scoped, or constitutionally
sound. So I ask you sincerely, can you
say you have honestly and faithfully
discharged your duties to the best of
your ability by declining that outside
expertise? Property rights do come with
responsibility, but my rights should not
be disinished because of someone else's
lack of responsibility. I respect that
someone some believe this ordinance will
save lives. Others have real life
experiences that suggest it represents
an overreach of government authority. I
am choosing Liberty because the greatest
threats to liberty rarely come from
irrational panic. They come from calm,
reasonable decisions that expand
authority just a little too far. And
this I vote against it. Thank you guys
for your time.
>> Appreciate you. Any more Jennifer?
All right, last call for in the house.
>> Dr. Renie, may we have a motion, please?
>> Mr. Mayor, the recommendation of the
public service committee is to approve
on third and final reading. And I would
so move.
>> Second.
>> Second by Mr. Crave.
>> Dr. Rainey.
>> Mr. Mayor, I would move to postpone
until February 9th, 2026 meeting of the
governing body.
>> Second.
>> Second by Mr. White.
All right. I typically I'd go out to the
audience, but I think you've already
told me you want this postponed on your
side, right? So, if it'd be okay with
you, we'll just go to the council and we
will um we'll talk about the uh
postponement and take a vote. So, at
this time, I'll ask the governing body
any comments on the postponement. Dr.
Aldridge.
>> Uh Mayor Collins, through you. Um first
and foremost, thank you to everybody
who's engaged on this topic over the
last couple of weeks. Um, I've learned
more about administrative warrants than
I've ever ever dreamed there was to
learn about them. Um, but I appreciate
that, um, you've taken your time to come
and talk to us or to show up at council
and coffee or to email or to make phone
calls. Um, I am going to be a yes vote
to postpone this tonight. Um, we have uh
two substitutes that have been submitted
um, for this um, ordinance and or during
the last week. Um there's a third one as
well and I just think that we really
need more time to have the conversation
and to um with all of you and to um have
some more input um as we find the best
possible uh way forward that we can
really put some guardrails on this so
that we are addressing. Um, I think all
of us would agree that there are
properties in our community that um have
been neglected and are abandoned or are
a health or a safety hazard, but we need
to make sure that uh this is limited to
those types of incidences and not um
broadly expanded or used um in air. So,
uh for that reason, I'm going to be a
yes vote to postponing tonight. and I
look forward to working with you over
the next two weeks uh so that we can get
something that uh might be agreeable and
have the protections that you see um as
being necessary.
>> Dr. Renie, did you want to speak?
>> Mr. Moody.
>> Yep.
>> Thank you, Mr. Mayor. Three. Want to
echo my colleague from war three. Uh
thank you for being involved in your
government. It's like I said, you guys
are our bosses. I will also be a
postponement. And if anybody sent an
email asking me a second time for
postpone, I do apologize if I did not
see that. But my intent was to for
postpone it to make sure that these
substitutes are available to the people.
So just want to clarify that. Thank you,
>> Mr. Escoel.
>> Thank you, Mr. Mayor. Through you as
well, I will support the postponement.
And um I think the one general fear I
see in this room, but I also see and
hear about uh fears in our city and
those are for no knock warrants and
those are for people's civil liberties
and human rights and uh those last five
words when he said the pledge of
allegiance with liberty and justice for
all that means all.
Miss Labour, did you want to
>> Excuse me. Thank you, Mr. Mayor. I also
speak in favor of postponement.
I think that obviously
uh the city could have better done a
better job in preparing this. It uh
definitely surprised folks. [snorts]
But my question, Mr. mayor is what are
we going to do in the next two weeks
besides come back to uh the public
service committee that I serve on
with um evidently [snorts]
numerous
uh
substitutes which may or may not have
uh been seen by our city attorney. I
mean what what are we going to do to
answer all of these questions?
Um in a satisfactory way. And and I
speak not as a
attorney certainly and
obviously there are a lot of people that
can argue the law.
I speak as a person who has dealt with
very difficult situations in abandoned
properties.
[snorts]
And when we adopted the International
Property Management Code
that gives the authority to some
individuals here that I work with and
respect. Uh
they're trying to [snorts] help
neighbors and help the community and
help property values.
if they don't have the tools.
Um, it's really discouraging.
And I I I hope you'll all think about
that
because I'm not sure what we're going to
do.
I've heard so many suggestions here
tonight that I'm
very curious as to how we're going to do
this. Mr. Mayor, um, evidently we'll go
to the public service committee and
wrangle it out maybe, but what
what what do the realtors want?
What what are we talking about here?
Because if we're arguing
Supreme Court law, I don't think that's
going to get us very far. And I do
believe that we've got to
have [clears throat] some trust in each
other.
Well, it without that it's kind of uh
difficult
for the people that have to do the job.
And I can assure you those people that
are that do do that job are good people.
And we can talk about what might happen
in the future.
Certainly uh anything might happen in
the future, might it?
But we want to protect our
neighborhoods.
We want to deal with properties that are
abandoned. You can't even find the
owner. You can't even find who has the
mortgage. You can't even find what's
going on. You board it up and you got to
come back again and there they are
squatting.
So, I hope we can come up with something
that'll satisfy people. But, um, I'm not
sure how that's going to happen. Mr.
Mayor, and uh all the different concerns
I heard tonight and the three
or at least three or maybe more, who
knows, by next week, uh
I I just really hope we can understand
that interpreting and acting on the
International Property Management Code
is something that communities do for
their own protection. Thank you,
Dr. Emmens.
>> Thank you, Mr. Mayor.
I think several of you brought up the
fact that right now there is a crisis of
trust in the local, in the state and
federal government. And we have to
figure out how do we get past that? And
that's a job for many of us that are in
this room. I'm speaking in favor of that
of the postponement because part of our
job has to be to clearly define why we
do need this. I mean, we absolutely have
to be able to explain to you why we need
why we need this. I've asked a couple of
times, can we do what we need to do with
what we have now on the books? And the
answer has been no. So, we have to
figure out how we can clearly articulate
what it is we need and then how we can
put together a piece of legislation that
accomplishes what is needed. Nothing
more, nothing less, but what we need to
do to keep Cheyenne safe. And the
reality is it may take more than one
postponement because two weeks is a
fairly arbitrary
deadline in my opinion. We need to keep
working on it till we get it right. So I
think um in regard to Councilman Labor's
question of what do we do? We figure out
how can we articulate it, what's needed.
I think you all have been pretty clear
about what you want and how to build
that into this document. So I'm gonna
I'm speaking in favor of the
postponement.
Anyone
else in the governing body on the
postponement?
>> Mr. Mayor,
>> Mr. Wolf,
>> thank you very much. Uh, Mr. Mayor,
through you. Um,
there's a lot that has happened in the
last several weeks.
Uh, we should all keep in mind that
the city already has the powers that it
needs. This bill is all about process
and establishing a process.
I appreciate that all of you have come
here to to try and tell us how you think
this process should work. I agree with
my um fellow council woman. Uh we really
only have a week to do this because the
public service committee meeting is next
week um and we have already several
substitutes. So those of you who want to
be involved in this discussion are going
to need to move pretty quickly to have
your specific views heard by people. Uh
and uh we would uh encourage you to do
that. I think this may take could take
all of February.
At some point, the committee is either
going to be able to adopt a what they
view as a compromise piece of
legislation or the committee may be
split and could come to this body and
say we make no recommendation.
But whatever happens at the committee
level, we need to hear from you at the
final hour um and let us know whether
the compromise is satisfactory to you or
whether you just would prefer that we
not take any action on administrative
warrants at all at this time. Uh and
all those outcomes are are certainly
possible and um they you just have to
figure out you as the members of the
public, we as the body, which one really
leads to better government,
uh a better city, uh a city that people
can be proud of, a city that addresses
its problems and um and I appreciate all
that you've done. I'm sorry if you
thought my comments uh were u not uh as
cordial as they might have been and and
Miss McCoy, I appreciate your comments
and I apologize um uh for uh not uh not
being as uh controlled as I usually am.
Um but
take your time, come see us, come
participate in this process if you want.
If you think we need to take more time,
ask us to take more time. And in the
end, come back and tell us whether or
not what the work that has been done,
which is the hard work of legislation,
which Representative Lucas and uh
Representative Wasserberger and
Representative Filer all know about and
I know about from 30 years working with
the legislature. Sometimes you can reach
an answer that everybody agrees with and
sometimes you can't. And uh we then live
with whatever result seems the best for
the resolution of a complicated and
important issue. Thank you.
>> Thank you, Mr. Mayor.
>> Dr. Renie.
>> Mr. Mayor, I actually
I'm a little off topic, so pardon me.
Um, not speaking for the postponement,
but just as an explanation of our
processes, we do not table items.
Essentially, if you lay something on the
table, it goes away and dies.
>> Um, so we we routinely will postpone
issues and we had a city attorney rule
several years ago that we can only
postpone from this meeting to the next
meeting. So, um, that is why you will
only see a two-eek postponement. And
sometimes we string several of those
together to sort something out. But I
wanted everybody to understand
um, at least in this instance how our
process has worked. Thank you.
>> Thank you, doctor.
>> Dr. Aldridge,
>> Mayor Collins, through you. I wanted to
respond um to my colleague um, from Ward
One about what is the next step. Um I'm
will be meeting on Tuesday night at the
public service center uh public safety
center um at 6 pm uh to work through um
this uh ordinance with anyone who would
like to show up with some local
attorneys. So if you would like to show
up at 6 p.m. on Tuesday night um at the
public safety center February 3rd um
we'll you'll get to see how the sausage
is made and have your input.
And no, a week from tomorrow.
>> We're on the postponement. Any other
comments from the governing body?
>> Hearing none. All those in favor of
postponing until February 9th, please
signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Those opposed? The uh postponement is
unanimously approved. Next item, please.
Number seven, ordinance, second reading,
annexing to the city of Cheyenne,
Wyoming, various tracks of land
completely surrounded by current city
limits in eastern Cheyenne. Generally
located south of Story Boulevard, east
of Powder House Road, north of Del Range
Boulevard, and west of Ridge Road.
I'm going to hold off for just a second
as people exit.
All right. This is the ninth iteration
of our city council goal that we started
in 2021 to annex county pockets and we
identify a county pocket as a area of
the county 100% surrounded by city
limits. We'll go out to the audience to
see if anybody wants to speak to this uh
post moment or excuse me this annexation
before us.
Anybody?
>> All right. Dr. Renie,
>> Mr. Mayor, the recommendation of the
public services committee is to approve
on second reading. And I would so move.
>> Second.
>> Seconded by Mr. Cagrave.
Comments from members of the governing
body on this ordinance to annex.
>> Dr. Aldridge.
>> Mayor Collins. I am just wondering if
we've had any additional um public
comments made to our um planning
department or um any concerns have been
brought forward by the residents in this
area.
>> Mr. White,
>> uh mayor, members of council, Conor
White, Planning Development Department,
uh not with this annexation. Uh this is
section 20 and the properties that are
east of Converse
property owners haven't expressed any
concerns. Um, again, they're still in
favor of the annexation. Then the other
two property owners being the city and
the school district. I think we're fine
with that as well.
>> Thank you, sir.
>> Mr. Moody.
>> Yep. Thank you, Mr. Mayor. Through you.
And uh just clarify public again if they
property owner has to be annexed, I will
grant them what they uh propose for
their property. Thank you.
>> Dr. Do you have comments, sir?
>> No, sir.
Any other comments from the governing
body on the annexation? Hearing none,
we're on second reading. All those in
favor, please signify by saying I. I.
>> Those opposed. The ordinance is approved
on second reading.
Number eight, ordinance, second reading,
amending the official zoning map of the
city of Cheyenne, establishing the
zoning classifications of AG
agricultural and MR medium density
residential for land loca, I'm sorry,
for land annexed to the city of
Cheyenne, generally located south of
Story Boulevard, east of Powder House
Road, north of Del Range Boulevard, and
west of Ridge Road.
>> All right. When we annex property, one
of the rules are we have to give it a
city zone so we know what to do with it.
Um, so this is the uh the zoning for the
last item and we make an effort to zone
it or establish a zone as close to the
uh existing uh zone in the county as we
can. And so we'll ask if anybody in the
audience want to speak to the zone
that's before us.
Hearing none, Mr. Dr. Rainey.
>> Mr. Mayor, the recommendation of the
public service committee is to approve
on second reading and I would so move.
>> Second.
>> Seconded by Mr. Crave.
>> Any comments from the governing body on
the establishment of the zones?
>> Hearing none. All those in favor, please
signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> And those opposed. The established zones
are approved on second reading. Number
nine, ordinance, second reading,
amending 5.7.3
accessory dwelling units of the Cheyenne
Unified Development Code to remove owner
occupancy and adjust parking
requirements for accessory dwellings and
making conforming amendments to the
definitions of necessary dwelling and
semi-attached dwelling under 1.4.4
descriptions of uses of land and
buildings.
All right, this has been a
recommendation from some of our
affordable housing task force and other
uh folks talking about u working on our
housing uh crisis. Uh this one is to
relax the accessory dwelling unit
requirements uh that being the owner
occupied uh requirement. Is there
anybody in the audience wants to speak
to that?
Mr. Dorsch, welcome.
Mayor Collins, members of the city
council, thank you for having me this
evening. Dan Dorsch, executive director,
Habitat for Humanity of Laramie County.
Just here to say I support this uh
amendment to the UDC. It's a it will be
a creative way to you add more housing.
Um we do have a pretty relaxed ADU uh in
our city already, but this is another
step to add more housing that we
severely need. So, thank you very much
and I stand for any questions.
>> Dan, thanks for being here.
>> You're welcome. Thank you.
>> Anybody else in the audience want to
speak to this?
Mr. Bloom, welcome.
>> Mayor, members, members of council,
council, Charles Bloom, playing
development director. Just want to give
a little bit of background information
on this. Not all of you, you all heard
this at the public services committee
meeting. Unfortunately, Seth couldn't be
here today, so I'm going to fill in for
him and he knows a lot more of the
details. But long story short, with this
one, uh, what we're doing is we are
proposing to remove the owner occupancy
requirement. So right now if you have an
accessory dwelling unit you have to have
that primary land owner living there and
then they can have a second unit and
that unit can be occupied by a family
member. It can be occupied by a renter,
another family, anybody. Um when that is
developed um they are developed in a
fashion that allows for a little bit
less building code um adherence because
you have an owner occupied structure. Um
what this does is this removes that
owner occupied requirement which means
that your new um [clears throat] two
unit your accessory dwelling unit will
be built to a little bit different of a
standard. Uh for example the uh two
units will have to have the ability to
independently turn off the water if
there's a water leak a little valve you
would put on there. Um or also they
would have to be able to control heat
you know in their units instead of
having the upstairs one um control the
downstairs one and vice versa. Um, what
this really does for us is it really
does eliminate a lot of the issues that
we see when these these two homes
get sold and then the realtor says,
"Hey, this is a two-unit. You can rent
both of them out." We typically run into
a lot of problems with those. Also, what
this does is it allows for what's
commonly referred to as flat over flat
housing units. What does that mean? That
basically means you would have a house
on top with a basement apartment. So
that's how is referenced here in the
code. One one other item that is or two
other items that are very important with
with this uh proposed change is it
changes the way that parking is uh
required to be provided on the site.
It's not waving the parking requirement.
It simply is saying that if you have a
two, three car driveway, you can utilize
that driveway for parking purposes. The
way it is phrased right now is you are
required to provide an independent
parking space. So this allows more
creativity and flexibility for these
housing units um in the community.
Um so with that, I'm open for any
questions that you may have regarding
this proposed ordinance.
>> Dr. Aldridge.
>> Thank you, Mayor Collins. I have do have
uh three questions for you. um on the
flat or flat. One of my questions at the
committee meeting was about um the
building code that requ would require um
egress windows in the basement. I know
that that's been a common problem for
instance in communities like Laramie
where around the university they rent
out uh basements commonly that do not
have egress windows and it becomes a
real safety hazard when there's only one
egress exit from the basement and in
case of a fire.
>> Mr. Bloom.
>> Mayor through to to Dr. Aldrich they
would be required to have a separate
egress window in addition well for in
the bedrooms in addition they would be
required to have a separate entrance and
exit to the unit.
>> Okay. Uh my second question is about um
parking. What I'm hearing you say and I
just want to make sure I understand this
is that um the parking would they would
still need to provide parking.
um they would they be able to rely on uh
street parking to account for their
parking. Um I can see one of my concerns
is that if you are renting a basement
apartment and you have two adults living
there and you rent the upstairs and you
have two adults living there. So now you
have four cars um and they don't all fit
on the driveway. Is are they and I mean
are we requiring that they have any
parking available?
>> Mr.
Mayor 32, Dr. Aldrich, that is a great
question. The way this is worded right
now is it lets it default to our unified
development code, which means in certain
cases, if parking is available on the
street, that parking place could be
located on the street instead of in a
driveway. And that is reflected at the
very end of section three of the
ordinance in new proposed section H.
>> Last question, Dr. Al.
>> Yes. as long as they're as long as
they're following Mayor Collins throughu
the um distance back from the setbacks
from the driveway and from the end of a
corner. I mean following all the
traditional uh parking ordinances we
currently have. Thank you.
>> Y mayor through you to Dr. Aldrich. Yes,
that is correct. Uh something we do
consider when approving on street
parking for required parking is number
one is entirely in front of the the
building and does it interfere with
driveways on the property or next door?
>> Thank you.
>> Did you have a third question?
Okay. Anybody else?
>> Just real quick,
>> Mr. Moody.
>> Yep. Thank you, Mr. Mayor. Three for
you. Thank you, Mr. Bloom. And I do
appreciate when I brought this to you
and uh Mr. Lloyd. We worked through this
and we worked out everything. So, I
really do appreciate working with you
and look forward to in the future
continuing doing more work with the UDC
code. So, thank you very much. I do
appreciate.
>> Anyone else in the audience want to
speak to this uh amendment to our
unified development code?
All right, hearing none. Dr. Rainy.
>> Mr. Mayor, once again, the
recommendation of the public service
committee is to approve on second
reading, and I would so move.
>> Second. Okay.
>> Seconded by Dr. Emmens.
>> Comments from members of the governing
body.
>> Yes.
>> Yep. Thank you, Mr. Mayor. Through you.
Um, again, thank everybody for your
public comment. Um I do appreciate
everybody all the letters have for
humanity the um Southeast Wyoming
builders association also the um
um housing committee as well affordable
housing committee I do uh ask my
colleagues vote I on this something I
looked at it's another way to have more
affordable housing it's a very simple
change so I just urge everybody to
please vote I thank you
>> Dr. Emmens
>> thank you Mr. Mayor, um I also want to
support this ordinance. Um one of the
things that that we've really talked
about is trying to be more creative with
housing options and I think this is a
great opportunity for us to expand a
little bit more and one more option to
make sure that we've got housing
available in the community. So I will be
a yes on this.
>> Mr. Escoelt. Thank you, Mr. Mayor. to
you uh just to show the community we're
not always growing government. This is
one of those where we're reducing
regulations. So we we do both.
>> Anyone else in the governing body? Dr.
Rainey.
>> Mr. Mayor.
Well, I have supported almost I think
I've supported every thing that's come
through in the way of trying to make
housing more available and more
affordable. I have a problem with this
one. And my rational, first of all, I
understood when we did ADUs and that the
the um principal land owner had to be
living in the main building. To me, I
thought that was a great way to help
maybe younger younger families get into
their own home and then they could have
an ADU and back to help them supplement
or pay their mortgage. And I thought
that was a excellent use of adus.
However, I I have to go um by personal
experience, mayor. I had a friend that
lived in an older section of Glendale,
California, and it was a very nice
neighborhood. But over the years, some
of the homes were bought up, torn down,
and apartments were put in. And those
that weren't didn't have that done had
ADUs put in, and they became two
rentals. and I watched that neighborhood
deteriorate over the course of the time
my friend lived there. And I do not
think,
again, if we're trying to also protect
or preserve our neighborhoods, I do not
think converting a lot into two rentals
is necessarily in the best interest of
the city. So, I will be voting no.
>> Other comments.
>> All right. The motion is to uh [sighs]
modify our unified development code. All
those in favor, please signify by saying
I.
>> I.
>> And those opposed?
>> No.
>> Dr. Rainey, Mr. Craver, or nos. The
ordinance is approved on second reading.
>> Number 10, ordinance, first reading,
creating chapter 8.72, private displays
on public property to prohibit the
unauthorized use of public property for
specified private displays.
>> We'll send this item to the public
services committee. Number 11,
resolution reappropriating the fiscal
year 2026 budget of the city of Cheyenne
according to the provisions of Wyoming
statutes 16-4-112
and 16-4-113.
>> All right. We do this I think on a
quarterly basis. Um and it's a
requirement to uh acknowledge when we
have u grants or things like that to add
to our budget or if we add something to
our budget. Uh we have to go through
reappropriation to make our our budget
balanced. Uh, at this time I'll go out
to the audience to see if anybody out
there wants to speak to this
reappropriation for this quarter.
Anybody
hearing? None. Mr. Escoel.
>> Mr. Mayor, the recommendation of the
finance committee is to adopt and I so
move.
>> Second.
>> Seconded by Mr. White. Comments from
members of the governing body. Dr.
Aldridge.
>> Mayor Collins. I ask for this to be
removed from the consent agenda. um
first and foremost because I think it's
important for the public to understand
um how this reappropriation works and
that it's a um an effort to continually
have a balanced budget, but also that um
there are many times where it's not
about um taking money from one fund uh
to another fund to pay for something.
Sometimes it's receiving money um or
when our departments do a really good
job of being fiscally conservative that
there is money that they have left in
their budgets that then can be utilized
um in other areas. And so I think it's
important, especially when we're moving
money around, that we have full
transparency and and that we have an
opportunity to um celebrate some of the
grants that we've received um that are
listed on this um document that was
taken to the finance committee as well
as um to celebrate uh those that are
fiscally conservative. I did have one
question and that's in the um general
fund reserves that we're take using to
offer a 3% cost of living increase for
our full-time and part-time city of
Cheyenne employees. Um if that also this
amount um of $554,000
uh $652 from the general fund reserve
and $160,777
770 from all other funds um also
includes that um cost of living increase
that was given to our police department
as well or if that will be a separate
action.
>> Madam treasure
>> Mr. Mayor through you um that includes
the police department. Thank you. Anyone
else in the governing body
hearing? None. The motion is to uh um
adopt the reappropriation. All those in
favor, please signify by saying I. I.
>> I.
>> Those opposed.
The reappropriation is adopted.
Number 12, resolution establishing the
city of Cheyenne's prioritized list of
projects proposed for potent potential
inclusion on the 1% specific purpose
sales and use tax ballot proposition to
be submitted to the qualified electors
of Laram County at the primary election
on August 18th, 2026.
>> You know, there's one thing I hate about
this process and that tells me how fast
time is flying because I remember it
wasn't seem like that long ago we just
did a six penny sales tax ballot and
here we are working on the next one. So,
the last five years have just flown by.
Um, but with that said, I'd like to go
out to the audience, see if anybody has
any comments on the uh list of six penny
sales tax projects that uh we're
proposing to put forward to the county.
Voters,
anybody in the audience?
Okay. Hearing none, Mr. Seagra.
>> Mr. Mayor, the recommendation of the
committee of the whole is to adopt and I
so move.
>> Second.
>> Been seconded by Mr. White. Comments
from members of the governing body.
>> Mr. Moody.
>> Uh thank you, Mr. May 3. Uh just a point
of information for the public. Could you
just uh tell them how it will be divided
in terms of the items so they're aware
of it in terms of what's a single item
and the uh public um the uh the first
responders one just so that they're
aware.
>> Yeah. Thank you, Mr. Moody. Uh the
answer to that question is we don't
absolutely know that yet. We had our
preliminary meeting last week of the
countywide six penny sales tax committee
that will actually put together together
the ballot. Um that's members of Alban
Burns and Pine Bluffs, two from each of
those communities. Two from Larmy County
and two from the city of Cheyenne. I do
think though that we know some of the
projects that will be standalone. The uh
Johnson pool will probably be a
standalone project. This building will
be a standalone project and I believe
the fire station will be a standalone
project. Uh Dr. Dr. Indie, were there
any others that you remember were
standalone
>> for our projects? Those are the main
ones
>> and the rest of those then will be
grouped with uh like items from the
other communities. Uh they have three um
areas that they they group them
together. Things that are infrastructure
will be grouped together. Things that
are public safety will be grouped
together and then things that are
community enhancement will be grouped
together. So that when you're voting for
um you know public safety, everything on
that ballot item will be a public safety
item. when you're talking about
infrastructure, they'll all be
infrastructure oriented items. Um, so
they'll be like, group like, and I
believe we're meeting again, and I
apologize, I don't remember, next week
or two, um, to finalize those groupings.
I think Albin is still working on the
last item as far as the pricing goes,
and then we'll have all of the last
minute pricing, and we'll start to work
on that ballot, and I believe uh, it'll
come back to us as a countywide ballot
for our approval um, before April.
>> Mr. Premier
>> Dr.
>> also it wasn't decided yet. Our 9
million for roads was close to the the
commission kind of wanted to have each
package or bundle be about $10 million.
>> That's right.
>> So it wasn't decided whether our $9
million for roads would be a standalone
or put in with some other smaller item.
>> Yeah. So stay by. I would think in the
next uh let unless the next month or
less we should have a really good idea
of what the committee has decided and
how things will prepare on the ballot
and we'll report that back
>> to answer your question Mr. Woody.
>> Uh yes sir. Thank you.
>> Thank you Mr. White.
>> Thank you Mr. Mayer. uh through you. I
just wanted to to compliment um my
colleagues on the way that we uh I
thought thoughtfully debated um the
projects that are going to go for our
portion of the sixth penny ballot this
year. This was my third six penny
ballot. Um being a member of council, it
seems like it gets harder each time. Um
never easier, unfortunately.
Um, and I certainly didn't get all the
projects that I wanted personally on
that ballot. Um, but I do think that we
came up with a good ballot nonetheless.
And again, just appreciate the the um
thoughtful debate and discussion that we
had at the last Cal meeting.
>> Thank you, Mr. Dwight. Anyone else?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Dr. Aldridge.
>> Mayor Collins. Um I just was
wanting to know I did receive an email
and I believe all of my colleagues
received it as well um with concern
about um possibly having having some
sort of a mechanism that um would give
uh instate contractors, engineers,
architects, building inspectors,
companies that were will be working on
these projects that go forward from the
six penny ballot. um some sort of a uh
ranking preference um similar to what
the state of Wyoming uses on their
projects. Um I don't know if that can be
written into the resolution um as as
it's presented to the voters or if that
is something that um is strictly done
through the bidding process by each
governmental entity. Um, but I think
that that is a concern um by this
individual uh that emailed us and I
believe that it's an appropriate concern
uh to think about uh that um if at all
possible we are using Wyoming uh
residents and Wyoming companies to spend
Wyoming tax dollars with.
>> Understood. Thank you. Anyone else,
>> Mr. Mayor?
>> Dr.
>> Just one two last things. The you
referred to the next meeting of the
joint committee. That'll be the third
week of February.
>> Okay. I knew it was coming up. I just
couldn't remember when.
>> And I think we do have the ability to
use the state's bid preferences if we
wish.
>> Thank you.
Other comments on the six penny sales
tax list.
>> All right.
We have a motion and a second. All those
in favor, please signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> And those opposed. The uh established
list for the six penny sales tax is
adopted.
>> Next item is number 14 on page three.
Resolution certifying compliance with
Wyoming statute 15-1-402
for the city initiated annexation of
various tracks of land completely
surrounded by current city limits
situate in western and southern Cheyenne
generally located east of I25 south of
the intersection of Westland Road and
Missile Drive north of West and East
Allison Road and east of and adjacent to
North College Drive.
All right. I think this is the 10th and
maybe the last iteration of our city
council goal to annex
county pockets. Uh we started in 2021,
we're going to end in 2026. And so it's
been a lot of work on our staff's part
and I really do appreciate that. At this
time, we'll go out to the audience. Does
anybody want to speak to the annexations
uh that are contemplated in this
resolution?
>> Okay, hearing none. Dr. Renie,
>> Mr. Mr. Mayor, the motion to approve
died for lack of a second. Therefore,
there is no recommendation.
However, for the sake of discussion, I
would move to adopt.
>> Second.
>> Seconded by Dr. Emmens. Comments for
members of the governing body.
Comments.
>> Yes. Yes, sir.
>> Dr. Aldrich.
>> Uh, Mayor Collins through you. I was
just curious about whether we've had any
new comments. Um I know that um our
planning department had shared one um
concern from a resident of that area
initially with us and I didn't know if
we'd had any additional since that.
>> Mr. White
>> uh mayor members of council Conor
planning and development department
mayor through you. No we have not had
any further comments for this um
initiation of the annexation.
>> Thank you sir. Anyone else?
>> Mr. Moody.
>> Yep. Thank you Mr. Mayor through you.
Um, again, as I said, public services,
there's somebody that's opposed
annexation. So, that's why I'll be in no
vote because again, property rights go
both ways. Thank you, Mr. Mayor.
>> M. Dr. Emits.
>> Thank you, Mr. Mayor. I want to take the
opposing view of my colleague in that I
think as a governing body, we have a
responsibility for everyone that's
impacted by an area, not just one
individual. Um so um I feel like the the
the fair thing to do is to um
move forward with this because obviously
no one else has shared any concerns with
it. It's for the welfare of the city
which we are responsible for. So
therefore I would encourage a yes vote
on this.
>> Dr. Aldridge,
>> Mayor Collins for you. Um I
Normally when there is um someone who
appears before us and is um wanting
talks to us about not wanting to have
their land annexed or sends emails or
contacts us, I am more than uh willing
to be responsive and to um take that
into consideration. And um many times
I've been a no vote based on that
information. However, with this um
situation um I don't know who the
individual is. I haven't been contacted.
That individual, to my knowledge, hasn't
shown up at a council meeting. Um, and
so it's difficult for us to make
decisions um if someone uh places a
concern but doesn't um follow up or let
us know on the council what those
concerns are or um what their um
objection is to that annexation. Um and
for that reason, I'm going to vote yes
tonight. Um, but please, please, please,
if if you're in this situation where
you're being annexed and you don't want
to be, you need to reach out to us and
let us know. We are great at a lot of
things, but we are not great mind
readaders. So, thank you for reaching
out and engaging if you're you have a
concern,
>> comments.
All right, hearing none, we have a
resolution before us to certify the
compliance for this annexation. All
those in favor, please signify by saying
I. I. Those opposed?
[clears throat]
>> No. Mr. Moody is a no. All right, we're
on to item number 15.
>> Resolution authorizing the submission of
an application by the city of Cheyenne
for state funding for the Office of
State Lands and Investments Unmet
Housing Grant.
>> All right. This is a unique opportunity
for us to uh get some um a grant that
might help facilitate uh some affordable
housing uh in our community and we'll go
out to the audience on that.
Mr. Dorsch again, welcome.
>> Thank you, Mayor Collins, members of the
city council. Dan Dorsch, executive
director for Habitat for Humanity of
Laram County. In early 2024, Magic City
approached Habitat uh to seeing if there
is some way we could partner. And I
said, "Let's talk." So, we sat down and
Magic City told us that they were
looking at changing the way they were
providing their services to their folks.
They were going from a group setting and
wanting to go to more independent living
for those who are able, providing more
dignity for their folks. And they said,
"We have land, but we don't know how to
build. Is there some way Habitat and
Magic City can work together?" And we
said, "Let's talk."
And over the course of the next year and
a half, we decided to try to put to not
try, we're putting together a project on
the northeast corner of Ridge and
Charles, uh, just off, uh, north of
Persing, just east of Ridge Road. And
Charles, that section of Charles is a
dirt road. And we said, this is let's
let's look at this this lot, this
section to build on. And so putting our
minds together, we came up with Magic
Meadows as the name for this project.
And it will provide 12 units, half
habitat, half magic city of uh an
inclusive community living together in
this little neighborhood on the corner
of Ridge and Charles. And it's an
amazing opportunity for us uh as
partners in the nonprofit world to come
together. We often work together, but
not in this capacity. in doing some
research when we were putting this
project together, we haven't found uh
another project anywhere in the country
that brings this type of nonprofit
partnership together to build homes for
both Magic City folks and Habitat. And
what's really cool about this is as we
were working through this project, it um
first of all, I should say, I apologize
some when I said half Magic City, half
Habitat, it would be um most of Magic
City's folks live in a rental unit.
Habitat as some of you are well aware of
are home ownership opportunities.
What may happen through this project is
that some of Magic Cities may qualify
for home ownership. So not only do they
have the dignity of living independently
but be through our program and through
our partnership have the opportunity for
home ownership, furthering their
dignity. So, this this application um is
similar for those of you who were on
city council when you approved the one
for Pong Horn Crossing um which I'm
proud to say is almost finished with
infrastructure. Uh this infrastructure
is way less intensive than um Pong Horn
Crossing because of a couple things.
One, this is an infill lot that has sat
unused for multiple years. Um, we are
getting 12 units on just4 acres of land,
taking advantage of the cottage lot
amendment for that the city approved
several years ago through the UDC. So,
we are taking advantage of that infill
lot, adding units where there haven't
presently been units. Because it is an
infill lot, it is already surrounded by
city road and infrastructure. Instead of
having to bring sewer hundreds of feet
like we did with Ponghorn Crossing, it
is already in Charles in the alley
directly behind the property. So the
resolution stated for 500,000 is much
less than for Pong Horn Crossing. It'll
be much easier for us as an organization
to manage this project with those grant
funds. And um we greatly appreciate the
city support not only for this project
but for affordable housing as it is a
huge need in this community. Presently I
believe there are between 800 and 900
folks waiting on the uh housing waiting
list for affordable housing in Cheyenne
alone at the housing authority. So, the
more we can do to add those affordable
units, the better. Um, and again, this
is an amazing opportunity and a
partnership for Magic City and Habitat
to build community and hope in our in
our city. Thank you very much. And I
stand for any questions.
>> Thanks, Dan. And I remember a year and a
half ago or so, we were talking about,
you know, challenging each other to try
to build more houses in Cheyenne. And we
went from, you know, a couple a year to
12 next this coming this year and then
hopefully 12 the next year and then
we're talking already about a much
larger piece of property. So, I really
love your vision and what you're trying
to accomplish. So, thank you for that.
Questions for the applicant?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Dr. Aldish.
>> Mayor Collins. Um, I just as a point of
information want to confirm the document
I'm looking at uh says it's for $1
million grant for unmet housing grant
program. Mr. Dorsch, you said 500,000.
>> We have an amendment coming.
>> Okay, great. Thank you.
>> You bet.
>> Is that Mr. Moody?
>> Yep. Thank you, Mr. Mayor. Uh, thank
you, sir. And just for a point of
information for the public, um could you
just say what Magic City Enterprise
Program does because I know that one of
my second cousins is in this uh
situation.
>> Mr. Dorsch,
>> Mayor Collins, through you, Council
Member Moody. Uh Magic City's mission is
to provide services to developmentally
disabled folks. Um there are
representatives of Magic City who can be
more eloquent about their own mission,
but um they they do a fine job of
providing those services to people in
our in our community.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Anyone else in the audience?
>> I guess we asked the question, we're
going to get a the official answer.
Thanks for being here this evening.
>> Uh good evening.
>> Let me bring that right down in front of
you
>> because I'm short.
>> There you go. Good evening, mayor and
city council. My name is Shay Sparks.
I'm the chief operating officer for
Magic City Enterprises. So, to speak to
your question, uh we support people with
developmental and intellectual
disabilities primarily through um the DD
waiver through the state of Wyoming. We
do that in a variety of manners. We've
got several group homes that we offer
247 supports to folks. Um we offer a lot
of supports to people who live
independently with their family members
and others. Um we provide a lot of
employment supports um and we also have
kind of branched out recently on our
residential supports. We're also
providing supports um through um remote
support technology in combination with
staffing. So I hope that answers your
question. Um but really we are very
excited about this project with Habitat
for Humanity. Um really because we have
the land, we wanted to build it, we had
no idea how. Um, in addition to that, it
offers um, housing for our folks. Um,
not only maybe home ownership, but
potentially rentals that will be
affordable because unaffordable housing
really impacts our clientele as well. We
have a lot of people either waiting for
housing vouchers or, you know, quite
honestly living in very slummy
environments because that's all that
they can afford. Um, so we're very
excited to present the opportunity for
people to have, you know, good living
environment that is also affordable. Um,
that being said, I stand for any
questions as well.
>> Mr. Seager,
>> Mr. Mayor, thank you. Congratulations on
the project. It's sounds wonderful. Uh,
being a Quanian, I need to ask, uh, if
you could tell us the genesis of your of
your organization.
>> Absolutely.
>> There you go.
>> So, originally, thank you for being a
Quanian, uh, Magic City was founded on a
grant that was wrote by the Quantis
Club. Um, the original grant was to do a
work program. So it was for folks that
had adult children with disabilities who
were had them at home giving them the
opportunity to go out and spend the day
elsewhere i.e. Magic City doing work
doing day program activities. Um and
that was in 1971. So we've been around
for over 50 years. Um obviously services
have changed but it is all thanks to the
Quantis Club of Cheyenne. Um and so
thank you.
>> Cool story.
>> Yeah.
>> Cool story. Anybody else for the
applicant?
Thank you for being here. Good luck with
your project.
>> Anybody else in the audience tonight?
>> All right. I don't hear any more, so
I'll go to uh Mr. Escoel.
>> Mr. Mayor, the recommendation of the
finance committee is to adopt and I saw
a move.
>> Second.
>> Seconded by Mr. White. Mr. Escoel.
>> Mr. Mayor, I move to amend the fifth
whereas to replace $1 million with
$500,000.
>> Second.
>> Seconded by Mr. wide. Anybody in the
audience want to talk about moving from
1 million to $500,000?
Go ahead,
[snorts]
Mayor Collins, members of the council,
Dan Dors, executive director, Habitat
for Humanity of Laramie County. Just a
brief explanation for the need for the
amendment. Because of the tight timeline
for the grant, we didn't have a real
estimate on the infrastructure cost, and
so we were just ballparking it at a
million dollars. Once we got that
estimate uh from a contractor on January
16th, that was the impetus for the for
the cost coming down.
>> Thank you.
Anybody else in the audience? How about
from the governing body?
>> No.
>> Yeah.
>> Go ahead,
>> Mayor Collins to you. Uh first and
foremost, I really appreciate this is
quite an outofthe box, I think. um
project that is um going to be really
interesting and exciting to watch.
>> Are you on the amendment?
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
>> Um I'm curious though as to whether
$500,000
um will cover all of the infrastructure
within the time frame that this is being
applied for and whether there is any
match on behalf of the city for the
$500,000.
>> Mr. Dorsch.
How good's your crystal ball? [laughter]
>> I think hopefully it's getting better.
Um, Mayor Collins through you,
Councilman and Dr. Aldridge. Um, our
goal for this project is to start
breaking ground on the infrastructure uh
this fall in October. Um, with the goal
of getting everybody into their homes by
Thanksgiving of 2027. And that's the
same timeline we now have with Ponghorn
Crossing. Our infrastructure is almost
done. We're going to be breaking found
uh getting foundations and starting
going vertical the spring with everybody
in by Thanksgiving. That is our time
frame. The the grant is for or the ask
for the in the resol in the application
for 500,000 that does include a $100,000
contingency put in there by the
estimator and the the contractor who
does this type of work just in case
things increase between now and October.
So, we feel confident that that 500,000
will be enough to um do all the work.
Also, um in in case there's any question
from the city council, we did file an
amendment with or not an amendment, I
apologize, we we f we went into an
agreement with uh through anou with the
city uh for Ponghorn because the
application for the infrastructure for
Pongghorn crossing the estimate and the
application was for 1.80881 808818
million and the bid when it went out
through the process came in at $2.03
million and so the city and Habitat
entered into an MOU stating the city
only pay the amount for the grant. So if
that the case and and when the bids
should we get the grant or excuse me
should the city be awarded the grant and
the estimates come up higher I'm certain
there would be some type of agreement
that we should could enter again.
>> Thank you.
Anyone else in the governing body?
All right. Hearing none, uh, we'll
authorize the amendment of $500,000. All
those in favor, please signify by saying
I.
>> I.
>> Those opposed. The amendment is adopted.
We're back on the main motion. Is there
any other comments?
All right. Hearing none. All those in
favor of the main motion, please signify
by saying I. I.
>> Those opposed. The resolution is adopted
as amended.
>> Number 16, resolution authorizing the
submission of an application by the city
of Cheyenne for state funding through
the office of state lands and
investments for a rodeo grounds
pedestrian t transportation
infrastructure grant and authorizing the
execution and submitt of all necessary
documents in support of the application.
>> All right, we'll go out to the audience
and see if anybody wants to speak to
that. Mr. Hersig, did you want to come
and
appreciate you sitting through our
meeting, sir? Welcome.
Thank you, Mr. Mayor. Tom Hersig, CEO
Shay and Frontier Days. Um, uh, this
project, uh, as as many of you know, our
park and ride land south of town that
we've been utilizing that's part of the
military base. Um, we're not even quite
sure we're going to get to use it this
year. We're really in a dilemma for a
long-term parking strategy for Cheyenne
Frontier Days. Um, the other thing that
we're looking at is, you know, the
competition from the from south of us.
Now we the ranch building their new
arena. We got the big concert venue at
out at Windsor and now CSU is having
rodeo events and concerts in their
football stadium. Um, so for us to to
make sure that we're providing people
with the best customer experience there
is, um, as much as we all love jumping
on a yellow school bus to ride to the
frontier days, um, it's probably not a
great thing to have to stand in line
sometimes hour and a half to get a ride
out of there at night. Um, this this
this uh what we've been looking at, this
is not a a new idea by any means. is
actually was in our master land use plan
back in the 70s to be able to park over
on the base. Um, lots of discussions
with the base back then and and it never
came about, but now now they're they're
willing to let us park on that piece of
that land there and and build a bridge
across I25, which will provide a great
experience for our customer to come in
here. Um, it's going to take a lot of
traffic, we believe, out of the avenues.
Um, uh, 8th Avenue can be a little scary
at night at Frontier Park. Um, we're
gonna, uh, it's planned to have 2400
parking spots over there, which, um, is
about a thousand more than what we have
at our parking ride now. So, um, it
would be a great would be a gamecher for
Cheyenne Frontier Days to have a parking
facility like this that, um, would be a
long-term fix for what we need to get
done. Uh it's a great opportunity
through the state uh where hopefully the
city and the county can help us a little
bit. Um keep in mind this project is
over, you know, the the $8 million. It's
going to be more like an 11 or 12
million uh project to do the parking
lot, the infrastructure on the roads. Um
we're not asking for that. We're asking
for some help to get that grant money.
Uh Cheyenne Frontier Days is is willing
to to pick up the excess of whatever
that might be. um through whatever means
we can. We don't think that if we let
this opportunity pass us by right now,
it may never come again. Um and I'm not
quite sure what we'll do for a parking
situation. So, I would stand for any
questions. Mayor,
>> questions for Dr. Renie.
>> Mr. Mayor, I um want to thank Mr. Hersik
for being here and um Tom. So my
understanding is that Shan Frontier Days
is expecting if we can pull this off to
contribute several million dollars to
making this happen. Is that correct?
>> Yes. Um Mr. Mayor through you. Uh Dr.
Renie, um sorry I'm a little out of
practice doing this. [laughter]
Uh yes. So if the project's going to be
11 million, um you guys put in a
million. Hopefully the county puts in a
million. We're going to put in the other
two million to fulfill that whole grant.
and then the other probably three4
million dollars for that parking lot.
That's all going to be on us and that's
that's going to be a a big lift for us,
but we just don't feel like we can pass
this by.
>> Okay. Thank you, Mr. Mayor, and good
luck to you.
>> Thank you,
>> Mr. Moody.
>> Thank you, Mr. Mayor. Three. Uh, thank
you, sir. Just a uh quick question. Do
we have in writing from the Air Force
base that we're allowed to build this
and also utilize that parking lot
permanently or is that a temporary
agreement? You know, I maybe can answer
that question. Um, we made an official
request to the Air Force and it's in
their chain of command now to uh to do
that. The challenge we have is the money
from the state expires I think is June
30th and so we have to make the
application now and if in fact the Air
Force does not approve that, we just
won't get the grant. But if they do uh
approve it and we hope that they will,
then we'll be in a position to uh have
those grant dollars available to be able
to do this work.
>> Well, thank you. that answer answers my
question.
>> Mayor Collins through you. I've had um
several uh emails about this since this
was proposed at the finance committee.
One of the questions that has been posed
is once this is built um provided that
the Air Force gives permission and
you're able to get all of the funding
situated and this grant is successful um
will there be um the availability to use
that um by other groups and
organizations that parking area? Um, for
instance, the farmers market this last
year was at um the fairground or the
frontier grounds and um parking was
quite a little crazy especially the same
weekend as the Greek um festival. So is
that going to be parking going to be
available for other uses or only during
that 10day period?
>> Mr.
Mr. Mayor through you Dr. Aldridge. Um,
so as far as Cheyenne Frontier Days, the
only the only period of time they that
we are going to be allowed to use that
without permission from the city and
from the military is the duration of our
event. So the rest of the time it is
going to be used as long as the city and
the air force base agree to those terms.
So there's really nothing. It's just
going to sit there and hopefully it'll
be able to be used. And I I think once
the infrastructure is in place, I can't
imagine that the military wouldn't let
the city use it or us use it for maybe
in another event at Frontier Park.
>> And I'm thinking, Dr. Aldridge, the
military has events like Fort DA Russell
days um you know, where they could park
there and then the risk of having cars
come in their secure um fence line would
not happen. They could park there and
they have a gate that they could walk
into the base and uh and do that. that
they had the state cross country meet
there just recently and it was really a
kind of a tough situation to try to get
the athletes and families onto the base
and so this might give us a a secure
area where they could be led off and
then through a secure gate. So we we see
a lot of other opportunities and for me
I think we have 290 people living on the
base and over 4,000 working there. Uh
you know having a pedestrian corridor
where maybe a greenway access for people
to get back and forth uh and have access
to our almost 50 milesi of greenway. So,
I think there's a lot of opportunities,
but the first one is the the parking.
>> The uh second question that I had was um
is the I'm assuming that with this cost
estimate of roughly $12 million that the
parking area will remain unpaved so that
you also aren't having to pay a storm
utility fee on it.
>> Mr. Mr. Mayor, through you Dr. Hidge,
that is correct.
>> Okay. Thank you. I just a comment is
that when I do the math on that, 2400
parking spots at for $4 million brings
it to about $1666
a parking space. And if it's 12 million,
that's significantly more. I don't know
what the going rate is for parking
spaces, but um that's uh quite an
investment for parking.
>> It's the bridge. Uh Dr. Aldridge, that's
so expensive. Yeah.
Anyone else?
Mr. Mr. Hersik, thank you for being
here.
>> Thank you very much. Appreciate it.
>> And thank you guys for what you do. I
appreciate you.
>> Anybody else in the audience want to
speak to this uh resolution before us
this evening?
>> Okay. Hearing none, Mr. Escoel.
>> Mr. Mayor, this item was reviewed under
other items for the agenda on the
January 23rd, 21st, 2026 finance
committee meeting. Therefore, the
provisions of title two of the city code
have been met.
Mr. Mayor, the recommendation of the
finance committee is to adopt and I so
move
>> second.
>> Seconded by Mr. White, before I go to
the city council um for comments or the
governing body, I just want to say thank
you to our new grant writer, Libby, and
to um our chief of staff, Amber. Uh they
this this came from the state land
investment uh out of the blue. we didn't
know was coming and uh we only had a few
days to uh um get this grant application
put together and they moved heaven and
earth to get that done. So just wanted
to say thank you to staff for that and
I'll go to the city council. Any
comments?
>> Dr. Aldridge,
>> Mayor Collins for you. I'm going to be a
yes vote on this tonight, but I really
want the public to understand that this
is um a resolution that allows the city
to apply for a grant for the $1 million
uh which and I understand from Mr.
Hersig's conversation is would be our
share of this. Um that this is not
coming from any my understanding is not
coming from any of our general funds or
any of our funds, but it is coming from
a grant that we're applying for that we
hope to be successful in.
Thank you,
>> Mr. Moody.
>> Thank you. Agree with my colleague. I'll
be yes vote for other reasons. Got to
keep Frontier Days going. This is a big
part during our tourist season. Bring in
more tourists, but also too from my
perspective, it'll help down for our
children and grandchildren as well too.
Bringing in more people. Thank you, Mr.
Mayor.
>> Comments?
Hearing? None. All those in favor,
please signify by saying I.
>> I. and those opposed. The resolution is
adopted. We're we had our fingers
crossed, Mr. Hersik.
>> Number 17A, preliminary plat for Dry
Creek Vista, City of Cheyenne, Laramie
County, Wyoming, located northeast of
the intersection of Frank Court and Rock
Springs Street.
>> All right, we have a preliminary plat.
We don't typically get a lot of
preliminary plat, but this one is a
little bit more complicated with a
vacation of a street. So, we're going to
take this in two steps. Is anybody here
today to speak to this preliminary plat
before us?
All right. Hearing none, Dr. Renie.
>> Mr. Mayor, the recommendation of the
public service committee is to
acknowledge receipt of the report with
staff conditions number two and number
three. And I would so move.
>> Second.
>> Seconded by Mr. Crave. Comments for
members of the governing body.
>> Mr. Moody.
>> Yep. Thank you, Mr. Mayor. Through you.
Um, does anybody know if any of the
neighbors that were impacted by this are
here or if they have any uh public
comment?
>> Um, we asked for public comment and I
didn't hear anybody, but is anybody here
from that neighborhood that would like
to speak?
>> No, Mr. Moody.
>> Thank you.
>> Anyone else in the governing body?
All right, hearing none. All those in
favor, please signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Those opposed. The uh preliminary plat
is acknowledged with staff
recommendations. Was it one and two, Dr.
Renie? two and three. Thank you.
>> Next item is number 22A on page five.
Appointment of Mike Bites to the Laramie
County Community Juvenile Services Joint
Powers Board and Christina Rufati to the
Mayor's Council for People with
Disabilities.
>> All right. The mayor doesn't get to vote
on these, but um I will run the the
election. Um would entertain a motion.
>> I would so move.
>> Second.
>> Second or first by Dr. Aldridge and
second by Mr. White.
Uh, all those in favor of the
appointments, please signify by saying
I.
>> I.
>> Those opposed.
>> The appointments are approved.
>> Voucher report.
>> All right. Is there anybody in the
audience or on the governing body that
would like to speak to the vouchers?
>> Hearing none. Next item.
>> Revenue report.
>> Same thing. Anybody want to speak to the
revenue uh either from the audience or
from the governing body?
All right. Next item. Announcement of a
public hearing to be held February 9th,
2026 at 6:00 p.m. in City Council
chambers, 21101 O'Neal Avenue, Cheyenne,
Wyoming, and via electronic conference
meeting to determine whether compliance
of annexation conditions required by
Wyoming statute 15-1-42
exists for the city initiated annexation
of 16 parcels of land totaling roughly
49.4 4 acres comprised of various tracks
of land situate in western and southern
Cheyenne. Generally located east of I25,
south of the intersection of Westland
Road and Missile Drive, north of West
and East Allison Road, and east of and
adjacent to North College Drive. Other
business.
>> All right, this is an opportunity.
Anybody in the audience want to speak to
the governing body under other business?
>> All right, hearing none. How about from
the governing body? Dr. Aldridge. Mayor
Collins, I just wanted to um say a a
huge thank you to um Police Chief
Francisco. Uh he and I had the
opportunity last Tuesday afternoon to
visit um with uh a large collection, I
don't know, 30 35 uh senior citizens
from across um all of the different
wards. and uh he uh was gracious enough
to answer questions for over an hour and
um made quite an impression on um those
uh women who attended. So, he was quite
popular. So, appreciated his willingness
to do that and to be the first um
participant in what's known as civic
conversations.
>> Anyone else in the governing body?
>> Mr. White, m
>> Mr. Mayor, we we won't be having a
meeting for a couple of weeks, but on
February 7th, uh Saturday morning, um at
10 in the morning, my colleagues, uh
Councilman Wolf, Councilman Lebornne,
and myself will be holding another W one
council and coffee, and that will be at
the meeting facility at Romero Park.
>> All right. I heard you bring coffee.
Is this a true story?
>> Yes, it's coffee and
>> and it's coffee and donuts. You can't
miss that. Anybody else under other
business? All right, hearing none, we
are journed. Thank you very much.